Kumar Gaurav



- kmrgaurav33@gmail.com
- in linkedin.com/in/heykumargaurav
- https://github.com/ikmrgrv
- 9035267321
- HSR Layout, Bangalore
- https://meliorism.ink

PROFILE

6 years of expertise in building software for various domains at scale, with a year involved in Technical Entrepreneurship. I have sound understanding of webtechnologies.

Looking for opportunities as full-stack developer and challenging role, preferably in smaller team with large responsibilities.

SKILLS

JavaScript, ES6+, VueJS, NuxtJS, ReactJS, ReactNative, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Deno, TypeScript, HTML, CSS, TailwindCSS, SaSS, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, ElasticSearch, Redis, Kafka, WebSockets, Golang, Python, Firebase, RemoteConfigs, RTDB, Supabase

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering

M S Ramaiah Institute of Technology 2014 – 2018 | Bangalore, India

Delhi Public School

2011 - 2013 | Bhilai, India

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Founder - ProspectoAI, Quido, Twople

Technical Entrepreneurship

2023 - present

- Harnessing my interest in Entrepreneurship, I started building my own company full time since January 2023.
- **Twople** was last functional with ~400 MAU and ~40 orders per month.
- With ProspectoAI, we automated many daily tasks around outbound based sales, and campaigns. We integreted Ollama to enhance messages and contents.

Quizizz [7]

Senior Software Engineer - FullStack

Feb 2022 - Feb 2023

- Established experimentation capabilities with the product pricing, which helped us take our annual plan from \$60 to \$144 with net increment in overall revenue from paid users.
- Split Quizizz app into micro-services for smooth scaling and development.
- Streamlined "Game-Settings" & "Reports" for uniformity in code, experimentations. Used <u>SOLID</u> principles to refactor.

Quiph Media

Senior Software Engineer - Web Lead

Feb 2021 – Feb 2022

- Responsible for web-app development while <u>pivoting from Qtalk to SuperShare</u>.
- Developed iOS app using ReactNative for SuperShare and ensured quality enhancement and feature addition to the SuperShare web app using NuxtJs framework
- Set up system to test crucial user-flows in an automated environment. The tests ran every hour or everyday based on their config.

Quinbay Technologies

Software Engineer

2018 – Jan 2021

- Designed and Developed BlibliPlay, a video-streaming service with live-streams, interactions and chat options from scratch
- Upgraded build tools, introduced Unit testing and established monitoring system.
- Organised various tech sessions, review sessions and training of new hires in JavaScript. Interviewed 20+ candidates for various senior positions.

ORGANIZATIONS

Open Source Softwares - VueJS, VueCLI, NodeJS

Contributor

Contributed in various NodeJS & VueJS project source-code including VueCLI Tool.

Successfully completed Hacktoberfest 2019, 2020 and 2021